Guide to the Caryl Phillips Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- September 2006 Acquisition, 1940-2006; 38; (40 boxes)
  - Writings
    - Novels, Playscripts, and Screenplays
      - A Distant Shore
        - Drafts, printouts, some corrected, 2003; 3 (Box 46)
        - Drafts, 2003; 13 (Box 47)
        - Drafts, [2003]; 18 (Box 48)
        - Drafts and related papers, [2003]; 21 (Box 49)
        - Drafts and research files, 2003; 9 (Box 50)
      - Giovanni's Room
        - Drafts and research files, 2003; 4 (Box 50)
        - Drafts and related papers, 2003; 9 (Box 51)
      - Hotel Cristobel, radio play
        - Drafts, 1998-2005; 9 (Box 52)
      - I Too Am America: New York City and Slavery, production for BBC, research, drafts, correspondence, 2004; 6 (Box 53)
      - A Kind of Home: James Baldwin in Paris, radio play, drafts, correspondence, 2004; 10; Includes 1 computer disk (Box 53)
        Available through Access Services: Uncat MSS 895 Disk #10; Baldwin in Paris drafts.
      - The Lonely Londoners, play, drafts, 2000; 5; Includes 1 computer disk (Box 53)
        Available through Access Services: Uncat MSS 895 Disk #11; The Lonely Londoners (script).
      - The Man Eating Leopard of Rudraprayag
        Adaptation to screen for Ivory Production of work by Jim Corbett.
        - Research and drafts, 1996-2003; 3 (Box 53)
        - Drafts, 2003, undated; 4 (Box 54)
      - Marvin Gaye, drafts, notes, communication, 1997-2000; 13 (Box 54)
      - Mystic Masseur
        Screenplay adaptation of V.S. Naipaul's novel, directed by Ismail Merchant.
        - Drafts, 1998; 2 (Box 54)
        - Drafts, 1998-2000; 18 (Box 55)
        - Drafts, notes, communication, 1997-2001; 11 (Box 56)
      - The New Country, projected television 6-part series, synopsis, 1980 (Box 56)
      - A New World Order, essays
        - Drafts, 1988-2000, undated; 7 (Box 56)
        - Drafts, correspondence, 2001, undated; 16 (Box 57)
        - Drafts, 2000-2001; 14 (Box 58)
        - Drafts, 2001; 4 (Box 59)
      - The Right Set: A Tennis Anthology, drafts and permissions, 1998-1999; 5 (Box 59)
      - Settling Down, 1979-1980 (Box 59)
      - Small Island, teleplay, drafts and correspondence, 2004-2005; 11 (Box 59)
      - Somewhere in England, drafts, 1997-2002; 6; Includes 1 computer disk (Box 60)
        Available through Access Services: Uncat MSS 895 Disk #12; Somewhere in England.
      - Strange Fruit, drafts, 1979-1980; 2 (Box 60)
      - Uptown Top Ranking, drafts, 1978-1979 (Box 60)
      - Visiting Professor
        - Drafts, 2002 December-2003 August; 7 (Box 60)
        - Drafts and notes, 2002-2005; 19; Includes 1 computer disk (Box 61)
          Available through Access Services: Uncat MSS 895 Disk #13; Visiting Professor October 24.
      - Where There Is Darkness, draft, 1981 (Box 62)
  - Reviews and interviews
    Arranged chronologically.
    - Derek Walcott, interview, 1992 (Box 62)
    - John Edgar Wideman, interview, 1994 (Box 62)
    - "The Beat of History," review of "None to Accompany Me," by Nadine Gordimer", 1994 (Box 62)
    - "Interview with Ian McEwan," unpublished, 1995 (Box 62)
    - "Extravagant Strangers," lectures, 1995 (Box 62)
    - "Interview with Graham Swift," unpublished, 1995 (Box 62)
    - "Interview with Salman Rushdie", 1995 (Box 62)
    - Allan Hollingharst, 1996 (Box 62)
    - "Review of CLR James: A Political Biography", 1996 (Box 62)
    - "Michael Ondaatje interview," unpublished, 1996 (Box 62)
    - "Review of Texaco", 1997 (Box 62)
    - "Amistad review", 1997 (Box 62)
    - "The Contagion of Liberty," review of Black Jacks, 1997 (Box 62)
    - "George Lamming Interview", 1997 (Box 62)
    - "Stuart Hall Interview", 1997 (Box 62)
    - "Boyhood," review, 1998 (Box 62)
    - "Prophet in Another Land", 1998; 2 (Box 62)
    - "Slaves in the Family," review, 1998 (Box 62)
    - "Afrocentricism" and "Marks," review, 1998 (Box 62)
    - "A Broken Pattern of Islands", 1998 (Box 62)
    - "Leeds United Life and Me", 1998; 3 (Box 62)
    - "The Last of the African Kings," "Poetics in Relation," reviews, 1998 (Box 62)
    - "On the Nature of Blood," and "The Ghost of Anne Frank", 1998 (Box 63)
    - "A Dream Deferred", 1998; 2 (Box 63)
    - "The Burden of Memory," review, 1999 (Box 63)
    - "Guyana Enigma," review, 1999 (Box 63)
    - Conde Nast article, unpublished, 1999 (Box 63)
    - "Promiscuities," review, 1999; 2 (Box 63)
    - "The European Tribe," new forward, 1999 (Box 63)
    - "Heart of Darkness," introduction, 1999 (Box 63)
    - "Derek Walcott," interview, 1999 (Box 63)
    - "White Teeth," review, 2000 (Box 63)
    - "The Myth of Belonging", 2000 (Box 63)
    - "The Enigma of Denial", 2000; 5 (Box 63)
    - "The Fortunes of Wangrin," review, 2000 (Box 63)
    - "The Native Son," introduction, 2000 (Box 63)
    - "Put Money in Thy Purse," review, 2000 (Box 63)
    - "Through the Fire", 2000 (Box 63)
    - "CLR James," review, 2001-2001 (Box 64)
    - "Giovanni's Room," introduction, 2001-2002; 2 (Box 64)
    - "Ground Zero", 2001-2002 (Box 64)
    - "The High Anxiety of Belonging", 2001-2002; 2 (Box 64)
    - "Race: Sport and British Society," review, 2001-2002 (Box 64)
    - "Reluctant Hero", 2001-2002 (Box 64)
    - "Stealing Beauty", 2001-2002 (Box 64)
    - "Strangers in a Strange Land", 2001-2002 (Box 64)
    - "Across the Sabbath River", 2001-2002; 2 (Box 64)
    - "Ignored, Resented, and Mocked", 2001-2002 (Box 64)
    - "Kilimanjaro", 2001-2002; 2 (Box 64)
    - "O," review, 2001-2002 (Box 64)
    - "United We Stand", 2001-2002; 2 (Box 64)
    - Interview WINN FM with Charles Wilkin, 2003; (1 computer disk)
      Available through Access Services: Uncat MSS 895 Disk #14; Interview WINN FM w/ Charles Wilkin, 2002 December, transcription 2003 August.
    - "America Tribalism", 2003 (Box 65)
    - "Beacon in Dark Times", 2003; 3 (Box 65)
    - "Confessions of a True Believer", 2003 (Box 65)
    - Fortieth Anniversary of "I Have a Dream", 2003 (Box 65)
    - "Out of Africa", 2003; 2 (Box 65)
    - "Sierra Leone: Darker than Greene", 2003; 2 (Box 65)
    - "Sierra Leone: Darker than Greene," research and communication, 2003 (Box 65)
    - "Signs and Wonders", 2003 (Box 65)
    - "Border Crossings", 2004; 3 (Box 65)
    - "English, Half-English", 2004; 3 (Box 65)
    - "Not Without Love", 2004 (Box 65)
    - "A Conversation", 2005 (Box 66)
    - "Do You Come Here Often?", 2005; 2 (Box 66)
    - "The Height of Obsession", 2005; 2 (Box 66)
    - "I Could Have Been a Playwright", 2005; 2 (Box 66)
    - "A Life in 10 Chapters", 2005 (Box 66)
    - "My City: Leeds", 2005; 3 (Box 66)
    - "The Power of Love", 2004 (Box 66)
    - "To sir with love", 2005 May- July; 2 (Box 66)
    - "Constance Webb obituary", 2004 (Box 66)
    - "The Silenced Minority", 2004; 4 (Box 66)
    - "Women Writing", 2004 (Box 67)
    - Printed articles, 1983-2006; 10 (Box 67)
    - Articles about CP
      - Interviews with Caryl Phillips, printed versions, 1998-2006; 6 (Box 67)
      - Interviews with Caryl Phillips, printed versions, 1998-2006; 7 (Box 68)
      - Articles about Caryl Phillips, 1998-2000; 6 (Box 68)
      - Articles about Caryl Phillips, 1998-2006; 15 (Box 69)
      - Articles about Caryl Phillips, 1998-2006; 13 (Box 70)
  - Visits
    Consists of correspondence and other documentation of Phillips' lectures and appearances.
    - Visits, 2000-2001; 14 (Box 70)
    - Visits, 2000-2006; 51; Includes 2 computer disks (Box 71)
      Uncat MSS 895 Disk #15; Miami University 2004 August 23.
      Uncat MSS 895 Disk #16; Slavery project chronology, plus slavery script.
  - Audio Recordings
    Organized under headings according to format.
    - Audio cassettes
      - Radio Merseyside, undated (Box 72)
      - The Belly of the Beast, 1996 (Box 72)
      - Slave Narratives, undated; 2 (Box 72)
      - Slavery, undated (Box 72)
      - Revoicing recordings of secret tapes Kennedy made during missile crisis, 2002 October 16 (Box 72)
      - WNYC, 2000 October (Box 72)
      - Interview, undated (Box 72)
    - Compact disks
      - Frontiers, 2002-2003 (Box 72)
      - Distant Voices: songs for the writers of Sierra Leone, 2004 (Box 72)
      - 40 years on the Cuban missile crisis, undated (Box 72)
      - Our Souls have Grown Deep Like the Rivers, undated; 2 (Box 72)
  - Oversize Papers
    - Mounted review of Dancing in the Dark, 2005 (Box 73)
    - Poster for "Border Crossings", undated (Box 73)
    - Poster for "New World Order", 2002 (Box 73)
  - Computer media
    - THE ATLANTIC SOUND (August 4th 1999), 2006-genm-1909-0001; 1 (Box 74)
    - BERT NOTES 2 AUG. 13, 2004, 2006-genm-1909-0002; 1 (Box 74)
    - HOME WARD BOUND 7/8/99, 2006-genm-1909-0003; 1 (Box 74)
    - THE ATLANTIC SOUND (3) HOMEWARD BOUND HOME PROLOGUE (Dimara Notes) EXODUS, 2006-genm-1909-0004; 1 (Box 74)
    - THE Atlantic SOUND (2) LEAVING HOME Charleston LIVERPOOL Research Notes for L'Pool, 2006-genm-1909-0005; 1 (Box 74)
    - CP's copy "DANCING in The DARK" Oct. 27, 2004, 2006-genm-1909-0006; 1 (Box 74)
    - Bert: Part I Cp's Copy AUG 13, 2004, 2006-genm-1909-0007; 1 (Box 74)
    - BERT II + BERT inserts Sept. 24, 2004, 2006-genm-1909-0008; 1 (Box 74)
    - Bert 3 -- CP COPY and Bert Notes, 2006-genm-1909-0009; 1 (Box 74)
    - BALDWIN IN PARIS DRAFTS, 2006-genm-1909-0010; 1 (Box 74)
    - The Lonlely Londoners (script), 2006-genm-1909-0011; 1 (Box 74)
    - Somewhere in England SIE1.WR1 SIE2.Wr1, 2006-genm-1909-0012; 1 (Box 74)
    - VISITING PROF. 10/24, 2006-genm-1909-0013; 1 (Box 74)
    - Interview (Cp. Copy) WINNFM w/ CHARLES WICKIN Dec. 2002 Transcrip. Aug 2003, 2006-genm-1909-0014; 1 (Box 74)
    - Miami University 23/8/04, 2006-genm-1909-0015; 1 (Box 74)
    - Slavery prog. :chronology -- Plus Slavery Script, 2006-genm-1909-0016; 1 (Box 74)
    - 9 FILES THE ATLANTIC SOUND (1) Atlantic Livrpool Charsltn newplans cruisshp Elmina oldplans Proposal Bananabt, 2006-genm-1909-0017; 1 (Box 74)
    - [Disch], 2006-genm-1909-0018; 1 (Box 74)
  - Restricted Papers
    Boxes 75-77: Restricted until 2050. For further information, consult the appropriate curator.
    - Restricted papers (Box 75)
    - Restricted papers (Box 76)
    - Restricted papers (Box 77)